<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Interviews with people who eat plant based foods, online shop selling handmade products such as plant powered snack bars. Thoughts and ideas on sustainability, yoga, food</title>
    <link>http://yomojo.co.uk</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2016 18:11:14 +0100</pubDate>
    
    <item>
      <title>Masoor Dhal or Lentils?</title>
      <link>http://yomojo.co.uk/baked/masoor-dhal-or-lentils</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2016 17:48:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>Rajiv Shah</author>
      <guid>http://yomojo.co.uk/baked/masoor-dhal-or-lentils</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s so easy, quick and cheap to make fabulous tasting lentils. You only need a few basic ingredients. This should only take you about 20 minutes to make.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/image-12.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;image-12&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;The ingredients&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Red split lentils (also known as masoor dhal)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chopped onions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cherry tomatoes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Diced red pepper &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chopped spinach&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ground cumin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cayenne pepper (you could use chilli flakes or powder)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Salt&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Olive oil&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;The method&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rinse 1½ cups of lentils and add to a large sauce pan. Cover with water and cook on a low to medium heat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/image-11.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;image-11&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Add chopped onions and cherry tomatoes—stir and continue cooking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/image-17.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;image-17&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Add one heaped spoon of ground cumin, salt and cayenne pepper to taste. Stir everything and continue cooking. You may need to add water while cooking the lentils but don&amp;rsquo;t add too much. It&amp;rsquo;s better to add the water as needed rather than pouring a large amount in one go, unless you want the dhal to be more like a soup. I prefer the dhal to have a creamy consistency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/image-15.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;image-15&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once the dhal is nearly cooked (the lentils will begin to go soft and their colour changes from red to orange), add the diced red pepper and stir. Cook for another few minutes and add water if required. Switch off the cooker and cover the sauce pan with a lid. The cherry tomatoes should now be cooked too and will have lost their shape too. Check the taste and add salt/cayenne pepper if required.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/image-18.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;image-18&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you are nearly ready to serve the lentils add the chopped spinach and cook for a few minutes on a low heat until the spinach begins to wilt a little. Switch the cooker off. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/image-19.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;image-19&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Add olive oil and stir well. You don&amp;rsquo;t want to cook the dhal anymore. The oil is added for flavour but you also don&amp;rsquo;t want to loose the nutritional benefits of the oil by heating it too much.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/image-20.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;image-20&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your dhal is ready to serve—eat with nan bread, rice or on it&amp;rsquo;s own with a simple salad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/image-10.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;image-10&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pasta and Flat Leaf Parsley</title>
      <link>http://yomojo.co.uk/baked/pasta-and-flat-leaf-parsley</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2016 19:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>Rajiv Shah</author>
      <guid>http://yomojo.co.uk/baked/pasta-and-flat-leaf-parsley</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sometimes I just want pasta without the sauce! I could make a vegan pesto but I like something even more simple—flat leaf parsley, garlic and olive oil. Three ingredients to make your pasta seriously yummy. And best of all—it&amp;rsquo;s so easy to make. I&amp;rsquo;m a big fan of uncomplicated things—food being one of them. Just because it&amp;rsquo;s so simple does not mean it lacks flavour or texture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;The ingredients&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pasta—spirals, twists or penne work well&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Half a bunch of flat leaf parsley &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Two cloves of garlic&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Handful of cherry tomatoes (optional)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Olive oil&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Salt and pepper&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;The method&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Heat water in a large pan. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/image-1.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;image-1&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While that&amp;rsquo;s happening wash the parsley and pick the leaves—set aside. Cut the garlic into thin slices and put into a large pan with olive oil. Cut the cherry tomatoes in half—set aside.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/image-6.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;image-1&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once the water starts to boil add the pasta—I put about five to six handfuls for two people. Gently stir the pasta for a few seconds to separate it. The pasta will only take a few minutes to cook so keep an eye on it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/image-3.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;image-3&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the past is cooking gently heat the olive oil so that it gets warm enough to release the flavour of the garlic into the oil. Once it gets hot enough turn off the heat—you don&amp;rsquo;t want to cook the garlic. Add the tomatoes and seasoning—mix well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/image-4.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;image-4&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/image-5.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;image-5&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check pasta—when you&amp;rsquo;re happy with it drain off the water and add it to the olive oil/garlic—mix well. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/image-7.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;image-7&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Add the flat leaf parsley and mix well. Checking seasoning and serve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/image-8.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;image-8&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember the only thing you want to cook is the pasta. Everything else is just warmed!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Bicicapace Cargo Bike—It&#39;s Italian</title>
      <link>http://yomojo.co.uk/baked/my-bicicapace-cargo-bike-its-italian</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2016 16:55:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>Rajiv Shah</author>
      <guid>http://yomojo.co.uk/baked/my-bicicapace-cargo-bike-its-italian</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve had the Bicicapace for nearly three years. Has it been worth keeping? It&amp;rsquo;s the most expensive bicycle I&amp;rsquo;ve owned but it&amp;rsquo;s also been the best bicycle I&amp;rsquo;ve ever had or ridden. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I started looking for a cargo bike in the spring of 2013 I had no clue what I was looking for, all I knew was that it had to transport enough food that I was going to make and also allow me to use it for just casual riding. I started looking at Dutch bikes, American long bikes, custom made bikes. It was all super confusing! Some of these bikes were very heavy, not practical for my use, too expensive and some reviews I&amp;rsquo;d read were not great. Things started to look better when I came across &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.londongreencycles.co.uk&quot; title=&quot;London Green Cycles&quot;&gt;London Green Cycles&lt;/a&gt; and a conversation I had with Rob from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reallyusefulbikes.co.uk/&quot; title=&quot;Really Useful Bikes&quot;&gt;Really Useful Bikes&lt;/a&gt;. The bike I wanted was small enough but with a large carrying capacity and in my price range—it was the Bicicapace. &lt;strong&gt;A beautiful handmade Italian cargo bicycle&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/bicicapace%20test%20bike.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;bicicapace test bike&quot;&gt; 
&lt;em&gt;Testing bike around Primrose Hill and Regents Park London&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.londongreencycles.co.uk&quot; title=&quot;London Green Cycles&quot;&gt;London Green Cycles&lt;/a&gt; had a demonstrator! I drove to London after spoking to the lovely people there and took the Biccapace for a test ride around Primrose Hill. The demonstrator had three gears and I wanted to make sure it would meet my requirements to cycle up hills. I&amp;rsquo;ve never enjoyed riding a bicycle as much as this! It was a complete breath of fresh air. And the best part is that I could carry lots of things if required without interfering with my riding. I was sold!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I bought the second Bicicapace they had in stock because I preferred the colour scheme of that one—it still had three gears. There is an option to have one with seven gears. They got the bicycle ready for me on the same day to take back with me to Leicester. The only extras I had put on was the pannier rack and frame lock. It already came with dynamo powered lights, hub brakes and a large 70lt waterproof front bag that is good for carrying up to 60kg!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Cycling should not mean that you have to wear Lycra or sports gear—you should be able to just get on your bicycle and use it for more than just getting fit.&amp;rdquo; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve had a few problems with it—one which was sorted out by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.londongreencycles.co.uk&quot; title=&quot;London Green Cycles&quot;&gt;London Green Cycles&lt;/a&gt; very quickly. A strange clicking sound coming from the crank a few months after riding the bicycle but they knew what it was and instructed a bike shop here in Leicester what to do and paid for the repairs. Brilliant service! My second problem—punctures, two within two weeks. Just what I needed—not! I don&amp;rsquo;t think the standard tyres they fit are good enough. I decided to fit Schwalbe Marathon Plus road tyres. The ride has improved even more and no more punctures—apart from someone pushing a pin through the side of the tyre. :(&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apart from the above I only have good things to say about the Bicicapace. People stop me to have chat about the bike or just have a chat. Lots of young people have said what a cool bike it is. There is much to like about this bicycle from it&amp;rsquo;s looks, it&amp;rsquo;s small size, great riding position, carrying capacity. It brings so much freedom to my daily life. I&amp;rsquo;ve cycled for thousands of kilometres, on hots days, in pouring rain, in the cold, on windy days, up really steep hills fully loaded and it has performed magnificently throughout.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/bicicapace%20front%20bag%20capacity.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;bicicapace front bag capacity&quot;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;It can carry about 40 of these containers with insulation—more without&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s only now that I&amp;rsquo;m finding the 70lt carrying capacity limiting. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure what I&amp;rsquo;ll do. I did add bags to the rear pannier but even then I sometimes need to carry more heavy items. Bicicapace are making a new model called &lt;strong&gt;Justlong&lt;/strong&gt;—maybe a rear box fitted to that would meet my needs plus the front bag? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only problem I have with using the bicycle here in Leicester is that &lt;strong&gt;our cycling infrastructure is not great—in terms of routes and the quality of surfaces&lt;/strong&gt;. When I was using the Biccapace for transporting food I would end up with boxes that had leaked because of poor surfaces—it&amp;rsquo;s a joke but that&amp;rsquo;s another story. The bicycle has been looked after but nothing excessive and it&amp;rsquo;s in great condition. Maintenance costs so far have been about £140 over nearly three years. That&amp;rsquo;s so much cheaper than a car! The only other money I&amp;rsquo;ve spent has been for the rear bags which I bought from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reallyusefulbikes.co.uk/&quot; title=&quot;Really Useful Bikes&quot;&gt;Really Useful Bikes&lt;/a&gt; for about £60.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/bicicapace%20side%20view.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;bicicapace side view&quot;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;The decals are no longer on the bike, apart from that it looks just as good&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best part of owning the Bicicapace is all the conversations I&amp;rsquo;ve had with people over the last three years and I still meet new people today—truly priceless.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cycling is an important part of the future and especially cargo bikes. If you&amp;rsquo;ve not tried one do so—it&amp;rsquo;s a game changer. I cannot recommend the Bicicapace enough, it&amp;rsquo;s one of the best handmade cargo bicycles produced today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can find more information about the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bicicapace.com&quot;&gt;Bicicapace from their website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leicester Market</title>
      <link>http://yomojo.co.uk/home/leicester-market</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2016 11:39:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>Rajiv Shah</author>
      <guid>http://yomojo.co.uk/home/leicester-market</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you live in Leicester or Leicestershire you have no excuse not to come visit Leicester market. You can buy some lovely fruit and veg at bargain prices. You just need to know a few things first.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tuesday, Wednesday &amp;amp; Friday are the best days&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Walk around the market first before you buy anything&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Buy produce that is mainly in season&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Not all the stalls are in the same place each day&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some people run two stalls&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;These are my favourite stalls: Hills, Cottingham, Lunn’s, Garcia’s, Pittard’s &amp;amp; Norton&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t help yourself unless it is clearly marked&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In the summer the produce can ripen very quickly—so look carefully before you buy. If you are not sure ask the stall holder&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Get to know the stall holders—it makes a huge difference&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you are concerned about whether to eat organic or not—have a look at the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ewg.org/foodnews/index.php&quot;&gt;The Dirty Dozen &amp;amp; Clean Fifteen&lt;/a&gt; to help you decide&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of the above ideas can be applied to fresh produce markets in other areas. If you have a local market use it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plant Based Eating</title>
      <link>http://yomojo.co.uk/home/plant-based-eating</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2016 11:27:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>Rajiv Shah</author>
      <guid>http://yomojo.co.uk/home/plant-based-eating</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Having a plant based lifestyle does not need to be complicated. Most of it is common sense but then sometimes the most obvious things are not straightforward. We&amp;rsquo;ve created a simple guide to help you think about plant based eating. It&amp;rsquo;s not a definitive guide—these are just my personal ideas on plant based foods. You can print this out and stick it on your wall. It will print to any size—it has been designed to print at A3.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Download your free guide: &lt;a href=&quot;https://jumpshare.com/v/p1Q1LAKyBy8uWdtfHpxg&quot;&gt;Plant Based Food &amp;amp; Eating Well Guide&lt;/a&gt;. We are not going to ask you to sign up to anything or ask you for your email. This is completely free.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/plant%20based%20food%20guide.png&quot; alt=&quot;plant based food guide&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yomojo Is Back</title>
      <link>http://yomojo.co.uk/home/yomojo-is-back</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2016 15:14:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>Rajiv Shah</author>
      <guid>http://yomojo.co.uk/home/yomojo-is-back</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Where have Zukini, Caajoo and Veggiebite all gone? And what is Yomojo?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since closing down Zukini we had setup another business make plant based snack bars but we soon realised that we wanted to do just more than that. Initially we were going to have three different businesses doing their own thing—that was not really going to work in the long term, and so we decided the best thing to do is go back to the beginning. We started all this with Yomojo and so it made sense to use the name Yomojo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the all new Yomojo website you&amp;rsquo;ll find recipes, interviews, ideas, anything we think interesting and we shall be selling handmade products—both food and non-food. We will be starting with the &lt;em&gt;plant powered&lt;/em&gt; snack bars very shortly.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>All New Snack Bars</title>
      <link>http://yomojo.co.uk/home/all-new-snack-bars</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2016 15:04:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>Rajiv Shah</author>
      <guid>http://yomojo.co.uk/home/all-new-snack-bars</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ve been working hard on some new snack bars. The range comprises of three bars:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lemon and Ginger&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Seeds and Goji&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fig and Coconut&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have reduced the range and changed the recipes to make the bars even better. Flavour and texture have both been improved. There is a bar for everyone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we first started selling the bars they were £3 each and that is something that did not sit well with us. We have now managed to bring the price down to £2 for a 67g bar. That&amp;rsquo;s really great value for a handmade bar with clean ingredients—using no refined sugars or palm oil either.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tomato and Red Pepper Sauce</title>
      <link>http://yomojo.co.uk/baked/tomato-and-red-pepper-sauce</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2015 18:22:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>Rajiv Shah</author>
      <guid>http://yomojo.co.uk/baked/tomato-and-red-pepper-sauce</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The recipe is back—if you have about 40 minutes to spare you should make this!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tomatoes, red peppers and onions—what could be more simple to make a rich flavourful versitile sauce? It’s simple to make and &lt;strong&gt;it will keep for over a week&lt;/strong&gt;. This is what plant based living is about. This recipe is very forgiving and so you can vary the ingredients by a fair amount and it should still work—well that’s been my experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you have lots of tomatoes, peppers and you don’t know what to do with them or maybe they are looking a bit tired—well what better way to use them! It’s a &lt;strong&gt;super simple recipe&lt;/strong&gt; using basic ingredients and it should not take you more than 40 minutes from start to finish. You will need a blender for this recipe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All you need to do is make some pasta, rice, beans or whatever and add some super delicous sauce. And a little sauce goes a long way! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Tomato &amp;amp; red pepper sauce ingredients&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3 punnets of tomatoes or equivalent&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3 red peppers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 onion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 tbsp dried oregano&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 tsp salt - this amount is optional&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 tsp olive oil&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3 tbsp apple cider vinegar&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Black pepper to taste&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;frac12; tsp cayenne pepper - this amount optional and you can omit it also
3 tsp tahini
3 tsp date paste or maple syrup&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/tomato-sauce-ingredients.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;tomatoes, red pepper, red onion&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Method&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chop everything roughly—if you’re using cherry tomatoes there is no need to chop them. Chop the onions finely&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Place the chopped ingredients and everything else—leave half an onion for later, except the black pepper, cayenne pepper, tahini and date paste into a large pan. Don&amp;rsquo;t worry if the pan is full, as you begin cooking it will reduce in volume&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mix everything and cook for about five minutes with the lid on and then stir everything again. Cook for another five minutes with the lid on&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Empty the contents of the pan into a blender and blend until smooth—just make sure the blender jug can take hot liquids. You can use a stick blender&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Put the sauce back into the pan, add the rest of the ingredients, mix well and cook for another five minutes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Check the seasoning and let the sauce cool for a while. You can then bottle it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the ingredients above I made about 2 ltr of sauce. It’s great for sharing—give some to family and friends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/tomato-pepper-sauce.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;tomato red pepper sauce&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Carys a geologist at the University of Leicester</title>
      <link>http://yomojo.co.uk/interviews/carys-a-geologist-at-the-university-of-leicester</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2015 08:58:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>Rajiv Shah</author>
      <guid>http://yomojo.co.uk/interviews/carys-a-geologist-at-the-university-of-leicester</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3&gt;Who are you and what do you do?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m Carys, a geologist at the University of Leicester, working on a research project to do with the evolution of tetrapods (the first large animals on land) in the Carboniferous, 350 million years ago - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tetrapodworld.com&quot;&gt;Tetrapod World&lt;/a&gt;. In my spare time I help to run &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.leicesterveggies.org.uk/&quot;&gt;Leicestershire Vegetarian and Vegan Group&lt;/a&gt;. We do a lot of local outreach and education about plant-based foods, such as cookery demos, talks, stalls and events like Leicester Vegan Fayre. Recently we launched a new &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.goleicestershire.com/food-and-drink/veggie-leicester.aspx&quot;&gt;Veggie Tourism initiative in Leicester&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;How long have you been eating plant based foods and what made you get into plant foods?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I went vegan 15 years ago, but started reducing meat, fish and then later dairy/egg consumption years before that. I choose to go vegan because I care for animals and wanted their suffering to end. I really love this quote from Edgar’s Mission, an animal sanctuary in America: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;- CARYS Bennet&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;If we could live happy and healthy lives without harming others&amp;hellip; why wouldn&amp;rsquo;t we?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Do you like making food and what are your favourite foods?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m a busy person with lots of hobbies and interests, so my favourite dishes are one’s I can cook in a hurry! Stir-fry’s, soups and salads. I also love winter comfort food like stews, pies and casseroles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Describe your day with plant foods.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I like to eat a lot of fruit for breakfast, to rehydrate and re-energise, so I have a juice or smoothie. On mornings where there is no time I have some toast or eat musseli when I get to work! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s your favourite kitchen tool/gadget?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My high-speed blender, called Optimum, from Australia. It’s amazing! Vegan mac &amp;lsquo;n cheese&amp;hellip; soups&amp;hellip; smoothies&amp;hellip; nut milks&amp;hellip; mmmm&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;What one food could you not live without and which food do you miss the most since switching to plant based foods?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love avocado! Cant get enough of it. I don’t miss any foods, but like vegan alternatives to creamy cheese sauces such as cashew cheese or creme cheese made with almonds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;What do you consider the most important foods in your diet and why?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I just like to eat a lot of fruit and vegetables, and I feel run down when I’ve eaten too much processed or junk food. They have the most nutrients and health benefits. I also like to eat carbohydrate and protein rich meals after going to the gym or exercising, and this is really easy to do eating plant-based.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Would you say your look and feel more healthy?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Its hard to say because I’ve been vegan for so long, but compared to meat-eaters I go climbing and mountain biking with, I’m at a better fitness level.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;How has eating plant foods changed you?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s been the best decision I ever made! Now I can sleep at night with a clear conscience. By campaigning for animals and helping others go plant-based it gives me hope for the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;What advice would you give to someone who is thinking about getting into plant based foods.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My advice is that it’s way, way cheaper than you think, and easier! Google, check out blogs, go to meetings, veggie restaurants, events etc. Try new things, and before you know it you have a new start in life that will benefit you, the animals and the whole planet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/carys-bennett.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Carys on geology fieldwork in the Scottish Borders&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Carys on geology fieldwork in the Scottish Borders&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nikki apprentice in horticultural maintenance</title>
      <link>http://yomojo.co.uk/interviews/nikki-apprentice-in-horticultural-maintenance</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jul 2015 17:29:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>Rajiv Shah</author>
      <guid>http://yomojo.co.uk/interviews/nikki-apprentice-in-horticultural-maintenance</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3&gt;Who are you and what do you?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hi I am Nikki, a 23 year old apprentice. I work for my local council doing horticultural maintenance. However my heart truly lies in conservation which is what I hope to study at Nottingham University next September!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;How long have you been eating plant based foods and what made you get into plant foods?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have been solely plant based since August 2014 and have never looked back! I originally went from vegetarian to almost vegan when I became intolerant to lactose. However since doing my research I now know there is no way I would every be able to consume animal product again as I know too much about the cruelty involved and also about the damaging effects these things have on ones health. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Do you like making food and what are your favourite foods?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love too cook but unfortunately I feel I currently do not have to time or space to do what I want to do in my kitchen. When I do cook I like to make things from scratch and add different ingredients as I go along, I never really cook with much of a plan! I just go with what tastes good!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Describe your day with plant foods.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My day with plant foods starts with cereal topped with flax seed and fruit and a cup of earl grey! I will usually have a salad for lunch, I like salads with grains, beans and pulses in of some sort or I have a jacket potato! I will also have more fruit at lunch time! Dinner is whatever is in my fridge I usually have vegetable with either rice or gluten free pasta or potatoes, I also like stir frys!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s your favourite kitchen tool/gadget?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would have to say my favorite tool is the knife my Dad gave to me, a J.A Henckels santoku! I literally use it for everything! But I&amp;rsquo;m pretty sure if I could afford to own a blendtec then that would be a sure fight for my favorite.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;What one food could you not live without and which food do you miss the most since switching to plant based foods?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The one food I could not live without is avocado, they are so versatile! I would probably say I miss a cream tea the most but I know this can be recreated with soy clotted cream and vegan scone mix so if I stop being lazy and figure out how to make these things then I wont miss anything. I missed cheese for about 3 weeks but not anymore :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;What do you consider the most important foods in your diet and why?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I like to try and eat in variety but I consider dark, leafy greens to be important and also nuts and grains.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Would you say your look and feel more healthy?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Definitely, initially I lost a bit too much weight because I didn&amp;rsquo;t realize I needed to increase my portion size slightly but now I know what foods to eat and how much of them I have a lot more energy and my conscience is clear, my skin is also a lot clearer than it was too! Bonus lol&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;How has eating plant foods changed you?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I feel a lot more aware, I feel like the old me was so ignorant. Eating the way I eat now is so much simpler and just makes a lot more sense. I know now that whatever I&amp;rsquo;m eating I can&amp;rsquo;t really go far wrong!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;What advice would you give to someone who is thinking about getting into plant based foods?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would say probably to take little steps at a time, some people find any transition easier if it is gradual. However without knowing for what reason the person is thinking about it I cannot customize my advice. All I can say is it is the best thing I have ever done in my life and I wish I had been living my whole life plant based. Also it is not hard at all! Its soo soo easy and very eye opening. I think we vegans sometimes feel like we are walking around with this big secret to life but we want to share it with everyone! Good luck and take care :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/nikki-warden.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;nikki with her parrot&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Slow Raw Porridge</title>
      <link>http://yomojo.co.uk/baked/slow-raw-porridge</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jul 2015 18:17:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>Rajiv Shah</author>
      <guid>http://yomojo.co.uk/baked/slow-raw-porridge</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This has been my go to food for a long while and it&amp;rsquo;s what we started ZUKINI with. During the recent National Vegetarian Week food demo at the Friends Meeting House it was a huge hit with everyone. What we really enjoy is that&amp;rsquo;s it&amp;rsquo;s really simple to make.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://player.vimeo.com/video/134602118&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;281&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A short video showing you how we make slow porridge. This is as good or better than overnight porridge. It’s easy to make—just follow the instructions on the video. We flake our own oats using a cereal flaker but you can just use normal oats or whatever else you want to. The quantities are approximate:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Slow raw porridge ingredients&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I cup of almond milk&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;frac14; cup of oats&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3 medjool dates&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Small piece of vanilla bean&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1tsp cacao powder&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 large apricot&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1tbsp pumpkin seeds&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;tsp coconut&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>John is a medical engineer—though bike trials is his love</title>
      <link>http://yomojo.co.uk/interviews/john-is-a-medical-engineerthough-bike-trials-is-his-love</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jul 2015 17:34:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>Rajiv Shah</author>
      <guid>http://yomojo.co.uk/interviews/john-is-a-medical-engineerthough-bike-trials-is-his-love</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3&gt;Who are you and what do you?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My name is John and I work as a Medical engineer, although Bike trials (sport of riding a bike over obstacles) is my main love along with music and freediving (breath hold diving).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/john-bike-trial-01.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;john bike trial on rock ball&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;How long have you been eating plant based foods and what made you get into plant foods?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been eating plant based foods my whole life (32yrs) as I was a vegetarian from a young age and went vegan around 12 years ago. My dad has always been a vegetarian and I just knew from an early age that I didn’t want to kill animals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Do you like making food and what are your favourite foods?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I like cooking when time allows however it can be a hassle on a standard week night when tired from work and wanting to fit in bike riding. So I like to make practical food like a nice big vegetable stew that will last me several days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Describe your day with plant foods.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On a typical work day:
Something naughty like vegan pain au chocolate or toast for breakfast, sometimes a healthy fruit smoothie. Naughty crisps or flapjack for a snack then sandwiches for lunch or something I can get out (often something from Currant Affairs if in town). Then if I’ve been organised I have some of my vegetable stew for dinner. My partner and I usually alternate who makes dinner and we often try new ideas when we have time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s your favourite kitchen tool/gadget?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our blender as it’s great for soups &amp;amp; smoothies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;What one food could you not live without and which food do you miss the most since switching to plant based foods?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t know if drinks count but I’d struggle to survive for long without tea (with soya milk).
I’ve been a vegan for so long that I really don’t have any desire for animal products. I often have vegan meats but I doubt I’d actually like the actual meat. When I first went vegan I remember really liking a type of soya cheese called Swedish Soft (by Winner who used to make Swedish Glace before Unilever took over).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;What do you consider the most important foods in your diet and why?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hearty vegetables (potatoes, sweet potatoes, carrots, cabbage, kale etc.) and things like garlic and herbs for flavour and health. I’m unusual I suppose in that I like simple food, a healthy soup or stew and I’m happy. I don’t really go in for gourmet stuff much except for special occasions. I like to view food as fuel for the body and eat what’s healthy however I do have the odd weakness and limited time to cook.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Would you say your look and feel more healthy?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s difficult to answer this one as I went vegan at the age of around 20 (12yrs ago) and although I do feel pretty healthy and strong I can’t compare to what I’d feel like if I’d been eating animal products all these years. I do think I’d be more overweight if I wasn’t a vegan as animal products tend to have more fat. I certainly don’t feel I lack anything and seem able to crash my bike without breaking bones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;How has eating plant foods changed you?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The food itself hasn’t really changed me however living in a way that is different to the other 99.5% does make you realise things such as how unsustainable animal products are and also how good people can do terrible things if they have been conditioned to believe it’s normal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;What advice would you give to someone who is thinking about getting into plant based foods?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Go for it. Going vegan is one of the best decisions I ever made J.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/john-bike-trial-02.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;john bike trial flying through the air&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lindsay working in marketing &amp; runs Leicester Veggie</title>
      <link>http://yomojo.co.uk/interviews/lindsay-working-in-marketing-runs-leicester-veggie</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2015 15:18:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>Rajiv Shah</author>
      <guid>http://yomojo.co.uk/interviews/lindsay-working-in-marketing-runs-leicester-veggie</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3&gt;Who are you and what do you do?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My name is Lindsay and for my day job I work in marketing, communications and business development, but in my free time I write a blog called &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.leicesterveggie.com&quot;&gt;Leicester Veggie&lt;/a&gt; where I post reviews of local vegan-friendly restaurants and occasional plant-based recipes I love to cook at home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;How long have you been eating plant based foods and what made you get into plant foods?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started the transition from a vegetarian diet to a plant-based diet in February 2014 and am now fully vegan. I had been vegetarian on and off most of my life, with a few periods of meat-eating as a teenager and young adult. My decision to embrace plant based foods fully was initially for health reasons - I had watched the movie Forks over Knives which was really powerful, and I had also seen how much my mom and her partner had benefited from a whole-food, plant-based diet. My mom&amp;rsquo;s partner is an ER doctor in the US, and his health has improved so much that he now extols the virtues of this way of eating to people that he treats.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With all that being said, while it was initially for health reasons, today I stick to plant based foods for the animals. When I was a vegetarian I had no idea that dairy cows suffered just as much (if not more) than cows raised for meat. And when I discovered that baby chicks are killed because they&amp;rsquo;re a by-product of the egg industry, my heart just broke.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Do you like making food and what are your favourite foods?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love love love to cook. I have always enjoyed being in the kitchen, but it wasn&amp;rsquo;t until I became a vegan that I started to feel really inspired. It started through my mission to recreate all my favourite non-vegan dishes and now I am constantly researching and testing out new meal ideas to keep things interesting. Some of my favourite go-to dishes include miso soba noodle bowls, tacos of any kind (potato, jackfruit, roasted veg, etc), lasagne, curries…. We eat very well in this house!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Describe your day with plant foods.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For breakfast I almost always have my favourite of avocado on toast. I mix this up sometimes by adding different toppings such as tofu, cress, sautéed mushrooms, etc. I also have the occasional bowl of porridge with almond milk and fruit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For lunch I either have leftovers from dinner the night before, or I make courgetti (also known as zoodles or courgette noodles) with pasta sauce and saut&amp;eacute;ed mushrooms. But if it&amp;rsquo;s hot I&amp;rsquo;ll keep it simple with a salad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For dinner I try to make something different every night of the week. I love soup, so we usually have some type of soup a few nights a week (miso, tomato and red pepper, carrot and red lentil, etc.). I also make a lot of Mexican food which I miss from my native Arizona. And of course we eat out a fair bit &amp;ndash; but purely for the sake of my blog ;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/lindsay-food.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;lindsay food&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s your favourite kitchen tool/gadget?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love my spiralizer. I eat courgetti all the time, so I get great mileage out of it. It basically turns any vegetable into long, thin noodles, so you can use them in place of traditional spaghetti in pasta dishes, or you can eat them raw in a salad. My second favourite utensil is my food processor &amp;ndash; which is essential in any plant-based kitchen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;What one food could you not live without and which food do you miss the most since switching to plant based foods?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t think I could live without avocados - what a depressing thought! At every stage of my evolving diet I have missed one type of food or another for a little while. When I went vegetarian it was chicken, and going vegan it was eggs. I was never a big cheese-eater, so that wasn&amp;rsquo;t a problem, but I do still occasionally miss the odd poached egg. Luckily cravings disappear over time, and I&amp;rsquo;ve certainly noticed that has been the case for me. Plus, while I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t normally advocate eating processed foods, there are some great meat and cheese alternatives out there for when you find yourself craving those types of dishes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;What do you consider the most important foods in your diet and why?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t say there is one specific, particular food that&amp;rsquo;s the most important, but all are important in general. I think it&amp;rsquo;s essential to get variation in your diet so you get all the vitamins, protein and minerals your body requires. An easy way to do this is look at the colors of your food and try to &amp;ldquo;eat the rainbow&amp;rdquo; every day. I also try to make sure I incorporate good, whole grains into my diet along with protein-rich foods such as nuts and legumes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Would you say your look and feel more healthy?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would say yes. I haven&amp;rsquo;t noticed a huge change, but then again I was already eating a mostly plant-based diet even when I was a vegetarian. The biggest change for me has been psychologically; I feel so much better knowing that no animals had to suffer for my palate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;How has eating plant foods changed you?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would like to hope it has made me a more compassionate person at most, and a better cook at least!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;What advice would you give to someone who is thinking about getting into plant based foods.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just go for it! Arm yourself with knowledge &amp;ndash; there is so much out there - and jump right in. Don&amp;rsquo;t worry if you slip up in the beginning - it&amp;rsquo;s easy to be hard on yourself but remember that by adopting a plant-based diet you are improving your health, helping the environment and eliminating needless animal suffering. I would also recommend joining a local vegan group and getting active on Twitter &amp;ndash; the online community is incredibly supportive. This will sound a bit hippie-ish - but just listen to your body and enjoy the journey!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/lindsay-belle.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;lindsay belle&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The great gluten-free diet fad</title>
      <link>http://yomojo.co.uk/baked/the-great-gluten-free-diet-fad</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jul 2015 11:14:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>Rajiv Shah</author>
      <guid>http://yomojo.co.uk/baked/the-great-gluten-free-diet-fad</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The BBC writes,  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Part of the controversy surrounding gluten sensitivity stems from the fact that it is difficult to disentangle any benefits someone may experience by adopting a gluten-free diet from the placebo effect - the power of a patient&amp;rsquo;s expectation that a treatment will lead to a cure.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A study published in February is the latest in a number of experiments with a &amp;ldquo;double blind&amp;rdquo; design, to sidestep the placebo effect. The Italian researchers tested 61 non-coeliac patients who believed they had gluten sensitivity, dividing them into groups that either received a daily dose of gluten or a rice starch placebo for a week, before swapping to the other treatment. Neither the patients nor the researchers knew until after the experiment who had been given the placebo first, and who the gluten first.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Many of the patients suffered symptoms including intestinal problems, foggy mind and depression while they were taking gluten, suggesting it really was the source of their problems.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The lack of physical biomarkers for gluten sensitivity also means that it is hard to know how many people are affected. Fasano&amp;rsquo;s best guess, which he has arrived at by looking at patient records, is 6% - a much higher number than coeliac disease&amp;rsquo;s 1%.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/magazine-33486177&quot;&gt;The great gluten-free diet fad&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gluten is a huge problem for many people and as the article points out it could be responsible for other problems that people are not even aware of. There is no cure but the easiet way to find out is to remove gluten from your diet completely and see if things get better.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jess 25 year old marine biology graduate</title>
      <link>http://yomojo.co.uk/interviews/jess-25-year-old-marine-biology-graduate</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2015 15:33:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>Rajiv Shah</author>
      <guid>http://yomojo.co.uk/interviews/jess-25-year-old-marine-biology-graduate</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3&gt;Who are you and what do you do?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m Jess, a 25 year old Marine Biology graduate currently working in retail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;How long have you been eating plant based foods and what made you get into plant foods?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the past few years I&amp;rsquo;ve been getting more and more into health and realised how diet is crucial to our well-being. Around October time in 2014 I stumbled across some vegan YouTube videos and was fascinated by how vibrant and happy these people were. So I did some more research, found out how beneficial a plant based lifestyle is, along with the horrors of the meat, egg and dairy industry, and went vegan the following month. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Do you like making food and what are your favourite foods?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love cooking! I&amp;rsquo;ve become so much more experimental with my food since starting this lifestyle. My favourite food has to be bananas, I eat them every day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Describe your day with plant foods.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most mornings I have a big smoothie that is usually bananas, greens and some other fruits. Lunch I like to have a bowl of banana ice cream topped with berries, flaxseed etc. For dinner I&amp;rsquo;ll have anything I fancy, such as home made pizza, veggie burgers, stir-fries or lasagne.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s your favourite kitchen tool/gadget?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have a three in one Kenwood that is a mixer, food processor and blender. It&amp;rsquo;s amazing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;What one food could you not live without and which food do you miss the most since switching to plant based foods?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I couldn&amp;rsquo;t live without my bananas. I don&amp;rsquo;t really miss any foods these days, although when I first transitioned I found cheese the only thing I really missed, but I found vegan alternatives and don&amp;rsquo;t crave it at all any more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;What do you consider the most important foods in your diet and why?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t consider any foods more important, a balance of different foods is most important to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Would you say your look and feel more healthy?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, I noticed within a week of transitioning that I felt more healthy and alive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;How has eating plant foods changed you?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s given me more energy, improved my mood and I feel much more aware of what I eat and where it has come from.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;What advice would you give to someone who is thinking about getting into plant based foods.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do your research and go for it! If you need advice there are so many people out there willing to help you!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/jess.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;jess selfie&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Luvin’ Summer Blending  Recipes</title>
      <link>http://yomojo.co.uk/baked/luvin-summer-blending-recipes</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jul 2015 18:05:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>Rajiv Shah</author>
      <guid>http://yomojo.co.uk/baked/luvin-summer-blending-recipes</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Below are the recipes of various things made during the Summer Blending demonstration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thank you to everyone that came&lt;/strong&gt;—it was a fun evening and the feedback we received so far has been really encouraging. We hope everyone got to taste most of the things that were made—we had only accounted for about 20 people but around 40 turned up! If you have any questions about the evening please contact us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The recipes demonstrated are just ideas for you to start thinking of different ways in which you can use a blender. It is by no means a definitive guide or the only way of doing them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just a few tips in using a blender:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s not necessary to use a VitaMix like I did to make most of the recipes. You could use something like a £50 &lt;strong&gt;Philips HR2162/91 Viva Collection Blender&lt;/strong&gt;—it has variable speeds. It will not make super smooth things but then there is a big price difference between the Philips and a VitaMix. It&amp;rsquo;s a good blender to start with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember if you do use a VitaMix the blades spin at a very high speed and things can get hot inside the container, so don&amp;rsquo;t blend for too long or &lt;strong&gt;use produce that has been chilled&lt;/strong&gt; first.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do use a tamper if your blender comes with one. They can be very useful in getting the blend process started.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reference to speeds I make are for the VitaMix so adjust accordingly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t overfill the blender, otherwise you could damage it—especially when you make things like ice cream or harder produce.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A silicone spatula is really useful for scraping the insides of the blender.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After using your blender wash it immediately! It&amp;rsquo;s a pain to clean once things start to dry up. It&amp;rsquo;s so much easier to wash the blender when it&amp;rsquo;s wet. One of the easiest ways to clean it is to half fill with water, add a few drops of washing liquid and spin for 30 seconds, discard the liquid and rinse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wash all your fresh produce first. Use a chopping board and a good knife. The knife I use is a Kitchen Devils tomato knife. It&amp;rsquo;s a great all round knife!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are concerned about whether to eat organic or not—have a look at the &lt;a href=&quot;href=%22http://www.ewg.org/foodnews/index.php%22&quot;&gt;The Dirty Dozen &amp;amp; Clean Fifteen&lt;/a&gt;. All the organic fresh produce I buy: salads, carrots, spinach, apples, bananas. Everything else can be a mix of organic and non-organic. I tend to buy mainly seasonal fresh produce with the exception of mangoes which I tend to buy all year round.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Places I shop in Leicester: Leicester Market, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wholefoodcoop.co.uk&quot;&gt;Wholefood Coop&lt;/a&gt;, local ethnic food shops and sometimes supermarkets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/kitchen-devil-knife.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;kitchen devil knife&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Sesame and date crumble&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ingredients&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
1 cup of sesame seeds&lt;br&gt;
6 to 8 pitted dates - if using Medjool dates about 4&lt;br&gt;
1 tsp cacao powder - optional &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Preparation&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add sesame seeds to a blender and blend at speed 7 until sesame seeds have been crushed &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add dates and blend at mximum speed 4 until dates are well incorporated into the mixture. This part should not take long, otherwise you&amp;rsquo;ll end up making a sticky mixture&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can eat this crumble mixture as is or add it to some fruit and yogurt. The way I use it is to cut some seasonal fruit, make a thick almond milk/cream (see below), add the sesame date crumble and coconut strips. Mix well and serve—preferably at room temperature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Will keep for two to three weeks in the fridge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/fruit-with-sesame-date-crumble.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;fruit with sesame date crumble&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Almond milk/cream&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ingredients&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;¼  cup of almonds - you can soak them if you wish—I don&amp;rsquo;t&lt;br&gt;
¼ whole vanilla bean&lt;br&gt;
1 cup of water—if you want to make a thicker creamy consistency milk, then use less water
2 Medjool dates (optional) for making the creamy version use about 4 dates &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Method&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;for smooth nut milk&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add water, almonds to blender - blend until smooth &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Put mixture in a nut milk bag (you can buy these from Lake Land and Amazon), and strain into a bowl or jug &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add vanilla and dates to almond milk and blend brieﬂy &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Method&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;for nut milk or cream&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add water, almonds, vanilla, dates to blender - blend until smooth &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Will keep for a few days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Hummus - bullet proof!&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ingredients&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
¾ cup of dried chickpeas cooked or about 300g of cooked chickpeas
½ cup of ground sesame seeds. I use de-hulled sesame seeds
1 cup of water preferably from cooked chickpeas 
1 clove garlic - be careful with the amount you use, too much can produce a bitter taste. You can leave the garlic out 
1 tsp salt, to taste 
Juice of one lemon &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Method&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add sesame seeds, water, lemon juice, garlic and salt into a blender - blend until mixed well &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add chick peas and blend—for a coarse texture blend at speed 7 for a short while and for a smoother texture blend at speed 7 for longer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The hummus will keep for 5 to 7 days. Best eaten at room temperature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This hummus is so yummy, easy and cheap to make—there is no excuse for not making it&lt;/strong&gt;! It tastes better than the one&amp;rsquo;s you buy from shops. Another big plus—it&amp;rsquo;s an oil free recipe. It will keep for five to seven days in the fridge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hummus-in-a-blender.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;hummus in a blender&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Gazphacio&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ingredients&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
1 cup of tomatoes for juice
2 cups of tomatoes
1 large red sweet pepper
¼ cucumber (remove the skin)
½ small onion
1 clove garlic
Handful of basil leaves 
¼ tsp cayenne pepper (optional)
Salt and black pepper to taste&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Method&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Roughly chop one cup of tomatoes place in a blender and blend at high speed until smooth. Set aside (optional-you can strain it to make it even smoother)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chop everything else and place into the large bowl&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;And the seasoning and chopped basil leaves &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pour the tomato juice over all the other ingredients and mix well&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Leave this mixture to marinate for a few hours or overnight in the fridge&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Place the mixture and blend at high speed until smooth&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Garnish with basil leaves and serve&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Will keep for a few days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Cantaloupe melon and mango smoothie with mint&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ingredients&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
1 cantaloupe melon
1 ripe mango
3 to 4 mint leaves&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Method&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add a few small pieces of mango to the bottom of the blender and then larger pieces&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add chunks of melon&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add the mint leaves &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Start to blend at low speed and then gradually move it to the highest setting and blend until you achieve a smooth consistency &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Drink immediately for maximum taste. It will keep in the fridge but the taste will change and also it will be cold—I think you should consume fruit at room temperature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you wanted to make a green smoothie just add a handful of spinach or kale. There is no need to put anymore than that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Watermelon juice&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ingredients&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Watermelon&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Method&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cut the watermelon into chunks with seeds&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Place into blender and blend at a very low speed - 1 or 2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Strain the blended mixture through a colander—make sure the holes are not too big or small. A sieve will not work&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can use the juice as a base to blend with fresh mango &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Spicy green buckwheat porridge&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ingredients&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
¼ cup buckwheat&lt;br&gt;
¼ cup walnuts&lt;br&gt;
¼ cup desiccated coconut&lt;br&gt;
¼ cup water&lt;br&gt;
2 bananas&lt;br&gt;
3 dates&lt;br&gt;
¼ tsp cayenne pepper&lt;br&gt;
Juice from half a lime&lt;br&gt;
Handful of kale or spinach&lt;br&gt;
Fruit - apple and shredded carrots  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Method&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Soak buckwheat and walnuts in water for one hour minimum and preferably overnight &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add coconut, bananas, water into the blender and blend until everything is mixed well &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add cayenne pepper, lime juice, dates, spinach and the buckwheat/walnuts after rinsing them in water &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Blend the mixture until a creamy mixture is achieved-you may need to use a tamper &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spoon half the mixture into a bowl, add apple/carrots and top with pumpkin/hemp seeds - eat immediately&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not many people wanted to try this! When you did, you were pleasantly surprised by how much you liked it. Just make it once and &lt;strong&gt;try&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/spicy-green-porridge.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;spicy green porridge&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Date paste&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ingredients&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
2 cups of pitted dates, you use whatever quantity you like - Medjool dates work really well for this recipe &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Method&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Soak the dates for four to six hours &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Strain the water from the dates. Keep the water &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Place the dates into the blender and blend until you achieve a smooth consistency. You may need to use a tamper to help mix the dates. If the mixture is too thick to start the blending process, add a couple of tablespoons of the water that you saved &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spoon the mixture into a glass jar and keep in a refrigerator. The date paste will keep for up to three weeks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Use the date paste in place of other sweetners such as maple syrup, honey, agave…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/date-paste.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;date paste&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Banana ice cream&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ingredients&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
3 Frozen ripe bananas cut into pieces-use slightly spotty bananas &lt;strong&gt;TIP&lt;/strong&gt;: peel and cut the bananas, then put in a container with a lid into the freezer or a freeze proof bag. They should be ready to use in about 12 hours
Enough plant milk just touching the blades. The recipe for the milk/cream above is fine to use
Ground ceylon cinnamon to taste—about ¼ to ½ tsp is good&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Optional&lt;/strong&gt; - 4 Medjool dates, desiccated coconut, 1 tbsp raw cacao powder &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Method&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Take the frozen bananas out of the freezer five minutes before use&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Put the bananas and cinnamon (optional: dates/cacao powder) in a food processor and process until soft and you get mounds forming. You will need to use the tamper or if you don&amp;rsquo;t have a tamper use more plant milk. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eat straightaway. You cannot freeze this and then eat it later!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/cacao-mint-icecream.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;banana cacao mint ice cream&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jarvis 22 year old living in presence</title>
      <link>http://yomojo.co.uk/interviews/jarvis-22-year-old-living-in-presence</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jul 2015 15:37:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>Rajiv Shah</author>
      <guid>http://yomojo.co.uk/interviews/jarvis-22-year-old-living-in-presence</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3&gt;Who are you and what do you do?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am me, Jarvis and I’m 22 years young, Right now I work part time and mainly love reading, living in presence, eating organic plant based meals and drawing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;How long have you been eating plant based foods and what made you get into plant foods?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I became vegan in October 2014 so roughly 8/9 months. I’ve always been very open minded and never attached to food, when I met my lover she was eating small amounts of meat mainly white meat but in general she was already on a healthy path and I carried on eating junk, pizza’s, microwave meals, heavily smoking, energy drinks, coca cola late at night… and then in early October I  began having major mood swings, I became emotionally unstable and felt I’ve got to change something so I adopted my lovers diet and after speaking with a colleague about smoking I quit and became vegan the next day, the transition was a lot easier with the support of my lover.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Do you like making food and what are your favourite foods?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love creating so making food is something I find joy in. My favourite foods are vegetables I do love broccoli, pasta and tomato dishes and I also love marinated curry potato cubes with a special dip I make with cashews and sundried tomatoes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Describe your day with plant foods.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I wake up, 1ltr of fluoride free filtered water… Breakfast: 5/6 banana smoothie with baobab and sesame seeds (once a week with organic coffee), Lunch: Pasta/ potatoes with a tomato or curryish kind of sauce and organic vegetables, I’ll usually snack on bananas and dates before my dinner which is similar to my lunch.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s your favourite kitchen tool/gadget?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Its got to be the blender I make all sorts of tasty treats and sauces in it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;What one food could you not live without and which food do you miss the most since switching to plant based foods?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bananas and dates!! I miss nothing this Plant based diet has increased my energy, cleared my skin, opened my eyes to life and I believe is helping me so much with my spiritual journey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;What do you consider the most important foods in your diet and why?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fruit and vegetables with plenty carbs a consistent amount of energy is something I truly value they tend to give me a very positive body high too, I’ve found that eating plenty vegetables everyday allows me go to that place of stillness and find clarity a lot easier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Would you say you look and feel healthier?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;YES! I love it, It has been a challenge because I went from tonnes of sugar and crap a day to nothing overnight but being able to access my natural energy and tap into my higher self is something I’ll never compromise again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/jarvis-selfie.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;jarvis selfie&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;How has eating plant foods changed you?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have compassion for all life on earth, I discovered a part of me I would have never found other wise, I’m able to get up and move, I can think sharper, my love life is stronger, it’s also made me realise that there’s so much that eating an organic plant based lifestyle can do for the planet and those close to us. By eating organic we reduce the amount of poisons that conventional farms use, allow other beings to live in harmony. By eating a cruelty free, organic and plant based diet we stop supporting obesity, we stop supporting modern day disease, pollution, animal cruelty and overall destruction of the planet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;What advice would you give to someone who is thinking about getting into plant based foods.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I simply say… Just do it forget thinking too much, your mind will come up with all kinds of excuses start looking at why, do it smartly. It requires only a few moments each day to jump on the internet and type organic vegetables and plant based eating.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Begin by reducing your refined sugar and dairy intake immediately, switch from those crappy sugar ridden bars to fruit, dates and bananas are a great place to start. Buy a stainless steel steamer, you’ll find that steaming veggies is so quick if you’re busy, buy a blender too, nothing fancy just one with a sharp blade. Step two replace conventional veggies and fruit to organic especially things you eat the skin of like apples and tomatoes, things you don’t eat the skin of are okay but try and get organic if possible; many super markets sell organic now and they’re easy to spot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reduce rancid oils, use organic coconut oil when cooking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make sure you eat plenty of carbs during the day such as pasta, potatoes, rice and bread with your meals it doesn’t have to be all of them in one day but pick and choose as you love.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reduce your meat intake to once a week or drop immediately. Start eating different types of beans such as butter beans, aduki, pinto, cannellini or haricot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Look to wholefoods for good health instead of products and supplements, they usually contain chemicals and unnecessary ingredients, take a few moments if you do want to buy a product and look at the ingredients, if you don’t know what something is, put it down and look online.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reduce sugar, meat and dairy intake or stop immediately if you’re well informed where to begin.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Buy a steamer and blender&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Get organic&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Look for bulk of rice, potatoes or beans&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Look online- Organic, vegan, plant based, rawtill4.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Meditate, meditate, meditate it goes like bum on chair with plant based eating ;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/jarvis-food.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;what jarvis eats&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Elizabeth project manager</title>
      <link>http://yomojo.co.uk/interviews/elizabeth-project-manager</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jun 2015 15:41:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>Rajiv Shah</author>
      <guid>http://yomojo.co.uk/interviews/elizabeth-project-manager</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3&gt;Who are you and what do you do?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m a forty-something mum of two young boys. I work three days a week as a project manager at a marketing company, trying to get a good work/life balance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;How long have you been eating plant based foods and what made you get into plant foods?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I became a vegetarian when I was about 12 when I realised that I had a choice. I’d always been a bit squeamish about eating flesh but back then you just did as you were told! My next realisation about eggs and dairy was a slow one but was affirmed by reading Juliet Gellatley’s The Silent Ark. I became vegan soon after that on 1st Jan 1997.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Do you like making food and what are your favourite foods?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No! I don’t like preparing food. Fortunately my husband does! He’s the savoury expert and tends to leave me to sort out cakes and desserts which I find much easier and more satisfying. Fruit is my favourite food, I could easily live on fruit and not much else. I like simple food like jacket potato with baked beans and VBites cheese. Pizza Express pizza is my favourite eating out meal, closely followed by the veggie Cornish pasty from Pengenna Pasties in Cornwall. One of my favourite dishes is my sister’s lasagne - so tasty! She also makes a delicious wheat-free option with aubergine. I only have wheat once a week (or less) so these meals are rare treats!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Describe your day with plant foods.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I always start the day with half a lemon squeezed into a glass of warm water - keeps the hunger at bay for an hour or two before breakfast. Breakfast is either porridge, buckwheat pancakes or a fry up! (scrambled tofu, mushrooms, tomatoes, baked beans). I don’t have much refined sugar or other syrups so I sweeten porridge and pancakes with grated apple and chopped apricots.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lunch is usually salad with quinoa, houmous or bean pate or my Monday treat is Zukini’s sweet potato wrap - delicious!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Evening meal can be something simple like a nut burger with potato and veg or something more elaborate involving beans or lentils depending what my husband has felt like cooking. I eat what I’m given!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Snacks would be a RawBite bar, homemade fruit &amp;amp; nut chocolate or apple and nuts. I don’t drink much else apart from water so get through a litre or two of that each day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;What’s your favourite kitchen tool/gadget?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This has to be our Vitamix. How did we manage without it? Soups and smoothies are so smooth and the way it mashes up dates and nuts to add to cacao is brilliant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;What one food could you not live without and which food do you miss the most since switching to plant based foods?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I couldn’t live without fruit (but do try to limit it due to the high sugar content). I honestly don’t miss any type of food but I suppose it’s nearly 20 years now so any cravings have long gone! I think I missed cheese a bit at first but now there are some great vegan alternatives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;What do you consider the most important foods in your diet and why?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Proteins - I’m aware my protein intake is quite low so I try to include a high protein food with every meal. It seems to be the food I find least appetising. Protein and good fats (eg avocado) fill me up well and I notice that a meal without them leaves me hungry soon afterwards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Would you say you look and feel more healthy?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I remember feeling a sense of inside-cleanliness for the first few months after becoming vegan but apart from that it’s hard to compare the difference. I’m a natural worrier so find that my sleep is often disturbed by my active mind and I think the amount of sleep I get affects my health as much as my food intake does. Exercise is also crucial for me to feel healthy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;How has eating plant foods changed you?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t think it has. I feel I was always destined for this lifestyle. It just feels very normal for me. I’m a Highly Sensitive Person see &lt;a href=&quot;http://hsperson.com&quot;&gt;hsperson.com&lt;/a&gt; and I think HSPs are much more likely to be vegan. I only learnt about the HSP trait a few years ago but it has helped me make sense of my life and being vegan is just part of who I am.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;What advice would you give to someone who is thinking about getting into plant based foods?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Find a mentor to support you and read up about vegan nutrition. Don’t be tempted down the junk food route. It’s very easy to be an unhealthy vegan - don’t assume you’re healthy just because you’re a vegan. See the sugar and wheat-laden offerings as an occasional treat not an everyday fall-back. Be careful to get enough omega oils and iron. Go for variety, it’s easy to find favourites and stick with them but try to be adventurous. There will always be people who don’t understand and never will. Don’t preach but live by example. Share the compassion. Enjoy the journey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/elizabeth-growing-pumpkin.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;pumpkin elizabeth has grown&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Pile of Filth</title>
      <link>http://yomojo.co.uk/baked/a-pile-of-filth</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2015 17:55:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>Rajiv Shah</author>
      <guid>http://yomojo.co.uk/baked/a-pile-of-filth</guid>
      <description>&lt;h4&gt;- The BBC writes,&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The Earth has entered a new period of extinction, a study by three US universities has concluded, and humans could be among the first casualties.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/science-environment-33209548&quot;&gt;Earth &amp;lsquo;entering new extinction phase&amp;rsquo; - US study&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;- Elizabeth Kolbert, writing for The New Yorker&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;@Pontifex tweeted to his 6.3 million followers Thursday, “The earth, our home, is beginning to look more and more like an immense pile of filth.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.newyorker.com/news/daily-comment/a-papal-message-that-spares-no-one-climate-change-encyclical&quot;&gt;A Papal Message That Spares No One&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You have to seriously wonder what is it going to take for people to wake up to all the destruction we cause and to do something about it. Man has this idea about being &lt;em&gt;entitled&lt;/em&gt; to whatever he wants—but at what price?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sarah nutritionist and adviser of the organic</title>
      <link>http://yomojo.co.uk/interviews/sarah-nutritionist-and-adviser-of-the-organic</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2015 15:46:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>Rajiv Shah</author>
      <guid>http://yomojo.co.uk/interviews/sarah-nutritionist-and-adviser-of-the-organic</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3&gt;Who are you and what do you do?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My name is Sarah I&amp;rsquo;m 19 years old and I&amp;rsquo;m an inspiring Nutritionist and adviser of the organic, wholesome and plant based lifestyle and I&amp;rsquo;m currently working my way towards that in all that I do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;How long have you been eating plant based foods and what made you get into plant foods?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been 100% vegan for about a year now. I started off cutting down on my meat consumption for health reasons, eventually I was only eating fish and chicken and then I suddenly went off them. I eventually educated my self about vegan nutrition and the impact eating meat and dairy has on animal welfare and the planet. From that day I then knew going vegan was one of the best decisions I could make and I will always feel it&amp;rsquo;s the best decision I have ever made.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Do you like making food and what are your favourite foods?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I absolutely love eating and cooking with plants, I think about it all the time. I have so many favourites; I love fruit so much like mango, Medjool dates, bananas, apples and kiwis. My favourite vegan warm dish would probably be a nice wholesome curry or spaghetti with lentils, tomato sauce and veggies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Describe your day with plant foods.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For breakfast I had a lovely banana smoothie, and for lunch/ snacks I&amp;rsquo;ve been eating loads of fruits like dates, mangoes and kiwis. Some days I eat RAW TILL 4 and then have a wholesome high carb dinner, like rice + veggies or sometimes I eat RAW TILL 12 and have a wholesome cooked lunched too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s your favourite kitchen tool/gadget?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the moment I&amp;rsquo;m loving the blender to make my delicious smoothies, I also love my steamer, I know its simple but it makes my veggies taste so nice and it doesn&amp;rsquo;t boil away their nutrition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;What one food could you not live without and which food do you miss the most since switching to plant based foods?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;FRUITS and VEGGIES, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t live without all of them and I miss no animal products at all, I&amp;rsquo;m too high on life with all the goodness plants bring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;What do you consider the most important foods in your diet and why?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Getting in my fruits and veggies in to feel nourished and eating enough carbs throughout the day to keep my energy up, it also ensures I don&amp;rsquo;t indulge on the high fat vegan foods which don&amp;rsquo;t agree with me if I have too much, for e.g. nut butters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Would you say you look and feel more healthy and how has eating plant foods changed you?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MOST DEFINITELY, high energy, clearer skin, more or less the body shape I want (with exercise of course too) but yes definitely, you just give your body an abundance of nutrition from the right foods for you and you can only feel your best from it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s opened my eyes to all the variety of plant based foods and the ethics that follow being plant based and overall it&amp;rsquo;s made me a more compassionate and considerate person for people, animals and the planet. I enjoy the simple things in life and I&amp;rsquo;m not wrapped up in a materialistic world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;What advice would you give to someone who is thinking about getting into plant based foods.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Be sure to research about plant based nutrition to make sure you are giving your body all that you need, try to avoid as much vegan junk as possible and stick to the wholesome foods like fruit, veg, legumes, whole-grains, nuts and seeds. It&amp;rsquo;s so much cheaper to make your food your self and it can be so simple (research). Make sure you eat enough too!! Overall enjoy the journey, follow vegan blogs, youtube channels, join vegan pages, people may be a bit negative around you but as long as you&amp;rsquo;re educated on veganism, following your beliefs and doing what makes you happy, that&amp;rsquo;s all that matters, there are so many people who have similar values that will support you in all that you do and I&amp;rsquo;m one of them. Always remember you have embarked on a great journey and I believe only positive things can come from this :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/sarah-jacques.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;sarah with a wholesome meal&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
